<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title> </title>
    <link>http://aranw.co.uk/tags/static/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Aran Wilkinson</author>
    <rights>(C) 2015</rights>
    <updated>2015-02-15 00:00:00 &#43;0000 UTC</updated>

    
      
        <item>
          <title>Static Sites Using Hugo</title>
          <link>http://aranw.co.uk/2015/02/15/static-sites-using-hugo/</link>
          <pubDate>Sun, 15 Feb 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
          <author>Aran Wilkinson</author>
          <guid>http://aranw.co.uk/2015/02/15/static-sites-using-hugo/</guid>
          <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://gohugo.io/&#34;&gt;Hugo&lt;/a&gt; is “A Fast &amp;amp; Modern Static Website Engine” or a static site generator. Hugo is a standalone application built with &lt;a href=&#34;http://golang.org/&#34;&gt;Go&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To use Hugo you write your content; posts and pages in Markdown it then generates static HTML files. These static files have no dependencies on expensive backend languages like PHP, Ruby or Python. It also doesn&amp;rsquo;t rely on a database. Hugo can build the static HTML files in seconds and it can generate thousands of pages and posts in seconds.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For my latest attempt at running a blog, I didn’t want the complexity of a system like Wordpress or other similar blog platforms. I also didn’t want install my own blog platform using a framework. I wanted a simple flat static site with HTML to reduce the risk of vulnerability to bugs. Frameworks and blogging platforms are at risk to potential software bugs and would put my own website at risk too. By using static HTML files, I don&amp;rsquo;t have to worry about this.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;They&amp;rsquo;re many different static site generators available; &lt;a href=&#34;http://jekyllrb.com/&#34;&gt;Jekyll&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://octopress.org/&#34;&gt;Octopress&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://blog.getpelican.com/&#34;&gt;Pelican&lt;/a&gt; and many more. I personally went with Hugo because of it being built with GoLang. GoLang is a programming language that I am looking to learn and use.  I thought running a blog generated with by a tool that was built in GoLang would be a good way to learn the programming language.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        </item>
      
    

  </channel>
</rss>
